Finding Aid for the Walter Gabrielson papers LSC.1830
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 3. Artwork, ca. 1975-2008
  - Scenes -- visual reference and drawings to consider (folder 5 of 5), undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Scenes -- preparatory drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Scenes -- preparatory drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Scenes -- complex -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Scenes -- confrontations -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Scenes -- inside buildings -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Scenes -- interiors -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Scenes -- exterior -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Scenes -- on hold [sic], undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Drawings considered for further development and then abandoned
  - Scenes -- visual reference for narrative paintings, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Scenes -- drawings and visual reference, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Scenes -- drawings not developed, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Science class -- preliminary drawings and visual reference, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Sculpture -- visual reference and drawings, c.a. 1995 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Includes several sketches for "Angels" series
  - Sets -- visual reference to develop into paintings, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Sets -- visual reference and drawing, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Small town fever -- drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Small town fever -- draft (folder 1 of 4), ca. 2008 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Contains parts of an artists" book
  - Small town fever -- draft (folder 2 of 4), ca. 2008 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Small town fever -- draft (folder 3 of 4), ca. 2008 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Small town fever -- draft (folder 4 of 4), ca. 2008 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Small town fever -- structure visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Small town fever -- structure visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Small town fever -- stores -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Small town fever -- people -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Small town fever -- character studies, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Small town fever -- visual and written outline, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Small town fever -- photographic studies, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Small town fever -- visual reference, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Small town fever -- selected drawings for future works (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Small town fever -- selected drawings for future works (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Includes a finished pen and ink drawing
  - Small town fever -- selected drawings for future works (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Small town fever -- written planning material, ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Small town fever -- characters source material, ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Small town fever -- drawings and photographic reference, ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Small town fever -- preliminary sketches for paintings, ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Small town fever -- Midwest photographic studies (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Small town fever -- Midwest photographic studies (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Small town fever -- Midwest photographic studies (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Small town fever -- textual research, ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Consists of records of paintings created and notes on research
  - Small town fever -- source material for paintings, ca. 1997 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Small town fever -- structure studies, ca. 1997 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Small town fever -- drama studies, ca. 1997 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Small town fever -- preparatory work, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Consists of various sketches and visual reference for small town interaction
  - Small town fever -- stories, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Consists of various newspaper clippings from small town newspapers across the country
  - Small town fever -- written source, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Small town fever -- cemeteries -- source material, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Small town fever -- fish -- source material, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Small town fever -- interviews [sic], 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Consists of short narratives about small town life written by Gabrielson
  - Social commentary -- drawings, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Source material -- drawings and visual reference used (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Source material -- drawings and visual reference used (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Source material -- drawings and visual reference used (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Source material -- narratives, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Source material -- drawings considered for development, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Source material -- written ideas for paintings, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Source material -- fragments [sic] (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    Includes miscellaneous drawings Gabrielson considered developing into art work or artistic series
  - Source material -- fragments [sic] (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Source material -- for development into paintings (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Source material -- for development into paintings (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Source material -- for development into paintings (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Source material -- preparatory work for artistic series concepts, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Source material -- points of reference, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Source material -- miscellaneous, ca. 2008 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Sports -- sports desserts, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
    Includes visual reference and sketches combining sports and culinary imagery. Oversize drawings placed in box 85, folder
  - Sports -- tennis -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Street scene piece -- visual reference and drawings, ca. 1991 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Studies -- barber shops, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Studies -- Barka, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Includes photographs and sketches
  - Studies -- buses and subways, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Studies -- carousel -- visual reference, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Studies -- carousel -- drawings, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Includes drawings and photographic studies
  - Studies -- diners, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Studies -- diner interiors, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Studies -- flying through the air [sic], undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Studies -- gas stations, 1975-1991 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Studies -- Grand Canyon, ca. 1999 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Studies -- houses -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Studies -- houses -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Studies -- houses -- visual reference, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Studies -- interior spaces, ca. 2003 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Studies -- Las Vegas, ca. 1992 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Studies -- mushrooms clouds, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Studies -- musicians, ca. 2001 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Studies -- movie theaters, ca. 1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Studies -- noir (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Studies -- noir (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Studies -- on the job, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Studies -- orange groves, 1985-1989 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Studies -- Paramount Pictures gate, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Studies -- people running (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Studies -- people running (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Studies -- people sitting on beaches (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Studies -- people sitting on beaches (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Studies -- phones, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Studies -- politics and elections, ca. 1992 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Studies -- restaurants and bars, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Studies -- red wagon, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Studies -- romantic embraces, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Studies -- running children, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Studies -- Santa Barbara, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Studies -- Santa Fe station, ca. 1993 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Studies -- sequential images, ca. 1997-1998 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Studies -- shrink [sic], undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Consists predominantly of drawings and clippings of comic strips
  - Studies -- Smokey, ca. 2002 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Includes drawings and clippings referencing the United States Forest Service"s fire prevention mascot
  - Studies -- street vendors, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Studies -- trading posts, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Consists of visual reference and drawings including several small drawings of musicians
  - Studies -- transportation, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Studies -- waiting room, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Studies (photographic) -- automotive garages, 1988-1991 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Studies (photographic) -- billboards, ca. 1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Studies (photographic) -- hardware stores, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Studies (photographic) -- hotels, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Studies (photographic) -- markets, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Studies (photographic) -- Melrose (folder 1 of 2), 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Studies (photographic) -- Melrose (folder 2 of 2), 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Includes pencil sketch
  - Studies (photographic) -- muffler shops, ca. 1988 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Surrealist -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 1 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Surrealist -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 2 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Surrealist -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 3 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Surrealist -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 4 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Surrealist -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 5 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Surrealist -- drawings selected for development (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Surrealist -- drawings selected for development (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Surrealist -- drawings selected for development (folder 3 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Surrealist -- drawings selected for development (folder 4 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Surrealist -- drawings considered but not developed, ca. 1998 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Surrealist -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Surrealist -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Surrealist -- visual reference and drawings (folder 3 of 4), ca. 1998 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Surrealist -- visual reference and drawings (folder 4 of 4), ca. 1998 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Surrealist -- music -- visual reference and drawings, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Sunset strip piece -- photographic studies, ca. 1988 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Unlabeled pencil drawings (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Unlabeled pencil drawings (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Unlabeled pencil drawings (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 1 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 2 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 3 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 4 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 5 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 6 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 7 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 8 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Unlabeled drawings (folder 9 of 9), undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Unlabeled drawings -- idea development (folder 1 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Unlabeled drawings -- idea development (folder 2 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Unlabeled drawing -- idea development, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Unlabeled drawings -- preliminary work to be developed, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Vernacular -- completed painting, undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Vernacular -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Vernacular -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Vernacular -- drawings and visual reference (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Vernacular -- signs -- visual reference, ca. 1991 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Vernacular -- food stands -- visual reference, ca. 1988 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Vernacular -- architecture -- visual reference, ca. 1988 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Vernacular -- drawings and visual reference for completed works (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1991 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Vernacular -- drawings and visual reference for completed works (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1991 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Vernacular -- visual reference (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Vernacular -- visual reference (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Vernacular -- ideas to develop (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Vernacular -- ideas to develop (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Vernacular -- ideas to develop (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 1 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    Consists predominantly of patterns for sculptural works
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 2 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 3 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 4 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 5 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 5 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 5 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Wall pieces -- pattern notebook (folder 5 of 8), ca. 1986 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and drawings (folder 1 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and drawings (folder 2 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and drawings (folder 3 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and drawings (folder 4 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Includes list of "future wall pieces"
  - Wall pieces -- Portland -- visual reference materials, ca. 1990 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Wall pieces -- New York -- photographic studies, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Wall pieces -- preparatory studies, ca. 2007 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Wall pieces -- drawings, ca. 1998 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and preparatory drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Wall pieces -- visual reference and preparatory drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Wall pieces -- ideas to develop (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Wall pieces -- ideas to develop (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Western series -- drawings, ca. 2000 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Western series -- written notes, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Western series -- bucking horses -- preparatory work for completed paintings (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Western series -- bucking horses -- preparatory work for completed paintings (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Western series -- bucking horses -- source material, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Western series -- chiefs -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Western series -- cowboy majestic [sic] -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Western series -- horse pattern, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Western series -- horses -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 2), ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Western series -- horses -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 2), ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Western series -- mystical horse [sic] -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Western series -- pony express -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Western series -- stage coach going thru desert [sic] -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Western series -- teepees and wigwams -- drawings and visual reference, ca. 2000 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Woodcut source materials and drawings, undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Works -- preparatory research for various projects, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Title lists and notes, undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Art Resource Publication, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    Includes correspondence and drawings
  - Paintbrushes and ruler, undated (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Gabrielson, Walter. 41 Airplanes. Dawson Aircraft Publications: Pasadena, CA, 1970. (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Gabrielson, Walter. Pop Dawson: the formative years. Dawson Aircraft Publications: Pasadena, CA 1971 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Oversize sketches, undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
    In oversize box.
  - Forever young sketches (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Forever young sketches (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Sports -- oversize sketches, undated (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Art Stripped Bare -- sketches, ca. 1998 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Symmetry of Guilt, 2008 (Box 86)
    Unfinished sculpture in special box.
- 4. Sketchbooks, 1976-2007
  Consists of dated sketchbooks with original drawings.
  - Sketchbook #50, 1976 fall- 1977 spring (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Sketchbook #51, 1977 summer (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Sketchbook #52, 1977 August-1977 October (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook #53, 1977 October-1977 November (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook #55, 1977 December-1978 March (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Includes note in front cover that sketchbook #54 is the cat book
  - Sketchbook #56, 1978 March-1978 July (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook #57, 1978 August- 1978 September (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook #58, 1978 October-1979 January (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Includes typed page titled, "Thoughts on paint"
  - Sketchbook #59, 1979 February-1979 May (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook #60, 1979 summer (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook #68, 1979 November-1980 February (Box 34, Folder 4)
    First page includes note "Continuation of the Oceania Journal", Includes drawings and some photographs from Gabrielson's time as visiting professor in Hawaii as well as thoughts on his return to Los Angeles
  - Sketchbook #69, 1980 March-1980 August (Box 34, Folder 5)
    Includes drawings and writings about James Turrell and his Roden Crater project
  - Sketchbook #70, 1980 September-1981 June (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook #71, 1981 June-1982 April (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook #72, 1982 May-1982 August (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Inside page titles the sketchbook "A Journal of Sports"
  - Sketchbook #73, 1982 November-1983 July (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook #76, 1985 June-1985 winter (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook #79, 1987 January-1987 September (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook #80, 1987 October-1988 Summer (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook #81, 1988 November-1989 October (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook #82, 1989 November-1992 September (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Number pasted on exterior of notebook is 80 but note on first page designates sketchbook as 82.
  - Journal: Ain't misbehaving jazz band, 2001-2003 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Includes notes about the band's performances
  - Journal, 2005 December 28-2009 September (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 2007 August 10 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Journal is predominantly empty.
- 5. Slides and photographs of artwork, 1962-2008
  Consists of photographic reproductions of Gabrielson's finished artworks and drawings. Also includes a limited number of slides from Gabrielson's personal life.
  - Early works (folder 1 of 4), 1962-1978 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Includes images of airplane drawings, small business survival, and prints
  - Early works (folder 2 of 4), 1968-1978 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Includes images of Arco Center exhibition with James Turrell, early water color drawings, and some numbered slides from 505-637
  - Early works (folder 3 of 4), 1961-1972 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Consists predominantly of prints, drawings and watercolors
  - Early works (folder 4 of 4), 1973-1977 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Early series, 1967-1975 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Consists of slide sheets labeled according to artistic series and exhibitions including 1972 Cirrus solo exhibition
  - Slides #613-624 and unnumbered slides, 1968-1977 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    Includes images of a sketchbook and the first "Clyde Book"
  - Slides #625-671, ca. 1977 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Slides #672-742, 1977-1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Includes installation shots from Gabrielson's exhibition at ARTspace
  - Slides #643-813, 1978-1981 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Slides #814-921, 1981-1983 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Slides #922-1073, 1983-1985 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Slides #1074-1135, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Includes slides of charcoal drawings and destroyed paintings
  - Slides #1135-1170, 1886-1987 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Predominantly consists of images of wall sculptures
  - Slides #1171-1257, 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Predominantly consists of landscape paintings and wall sculptures. Excludes numbered "Vernacular" series.
  - Slides #1258-1363, 1989-1991 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Excludes numbered "Vernacular" series
  - Slides #1364-1475, 1991-1993 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Includes "Faces" series and horizontal narratives. Excludes numbered "Vernacular" series.
  - Slides # 1475-1633, 1993-1996 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Slides #1634-1727, 1996-1998 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Slides #1728-1792, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Includes "Goodby from" series
  - Slides -- airplane works, 1968-1991 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Slides -- Karl Bornstein representation, 1974-1988 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Slides -- social commentary, 1977-1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- watercolors and sketches, 1978-1982 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Slides -- nature paintings, 1985-1989 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Includes title sheets with corresponding slide numbers
  - Slides -- commissions, 1986-1993 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Includes images of work purchased by the Hilton Hotel, work created for the Veterans Association, and H.H. Leonard's.
  - Slides -- new Monet, 1988-2002 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Includes collection of slides Gabrielson collected and submitted to an online art dealer
  - Slides -- small series, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Includes caricatures, chocolate series, and new airplanes series
  - Slides -- vernacular, 1988-1991 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Slides -- flowers and clouds, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Slides -- drawings, 1990-1992 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- San Diego, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Slides -- wall pieces, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Slides -- angels, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Slides -- art book, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Slides -- good eats, 2001-2008 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Slides -- lawyer, 2003-2005 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Slides -- poker face, 2003-2005 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Title sheets for slides, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)